Howie Hao Wang

About Me *watch a video

A web designer / developer based in the US with a background in architecture.

I am always willing to embrace new technology. At school, I took programming courses like <u>Data Visualization</u> and <u>Grasshopper</u>. My professional experience started at WeWork. I was fascinated by how a data-driven approach is implemented in design. Later at SOM, I worked on <u>an interior project involving VR</u>. In my spare time, I <u>self-taught programming</u> and gradually realized my true passion for web development.

My diverse background prepares me with both design and develop skills: A keen eye for design; professional experience using design tools; solve real-world problems by design thinking, research and analytical skills.

Education

University of Virginia

Aug. 2015 - Dec. 2017 | Charlottesville, VA

Master of Architecture, GPA: 3.61, Scholarship Recipient GRE: 319 *Full score in Math.

University of Mining and Technology

Sep. 2010 - Jul. 2015 | Xuzhou, China Bachelor of Architecture, GPA: 3.89, Rank: 2/86, Full Scholarship Recipient

Certifications

Next.js & React: The Complete Guide Jan. 23, 2022

React: The Complete Guide

Dec. 30, 2021

Node, Express, MongoDB Bootcamp

Sep. 20, 2021

The Complete JavaScript Course 2021

Jul. 15, 2021

Build Responsive Real-World Websites Sep. 8, 2021

The Complete 2021 Web Development Bootcamp Apr. 9, 2021

<u>howiewang2020@gmail.com</u>

(1) 434-227-8996

howiework.com

github.com/HowieWork

Projects

Snap App | MERN-stack web application

Share, navigation, architecture, plan. Snap App focuses on creating a photo sharing platform for people who love architecture. Inspired by real-life experience as an architectural designer. Read full story of Snap App.

Lunch Break | Built with Next.js

A blog site cares about work-life balance focusing on design, psychology and community. It derived from my own Wechat Official Account. The first article has reached 826 reads. Over 20,000 words have been published since launching. Read why and how I built Lunch Break.

Howiework | Built with React

I completely redesign and rebuild my portfolio website using React. It is a major update from <u>previous design version</u> for my aspiring dev career.

Museum - NMAAHC | UI/UX design project

A mobile app design for a museum. Goal is to enhance visiting experience. Personal product project contains the whole process including UX research.

*Below is a list of tutorial projects. I am currently working on adding more features and customizing these projects. Stay tuned!

Natours | Built with Node, Express, MongoDB

A web app for helping people choose where to travel in North America.

Forkify | Built with HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Search over 1,000,000 recipes. Find your favorite recipe and bookmark it.

Experience

Work

Web Developer at Sunwater Institute

Mar. 2022 — present | Bethesda, MD

Working on products: create, discuss, and implement fundamental ideas that advance liberty, knowledge, and power of individuals and society.

Consultant | Freelance

Mar. 2020 — present | Washington DC

Help clients rebranding; build portfolio sites with Wordpress/Squarespace. Worked on projects like Snap App, NMAAHC mobile app redesign.

Product Designer / Developer

Jul. 2019 — Mar. 2020 | Remote

Worked on MIAO product. Helped customer successfully rebrand their product, website using JS, HTML, CSS and integrate with their store-front design.

Architectural Professional at Skidmore, Owings & Merrill LLP (SOM)

Jun. 2018 — Jul. 2019 | Washington DC

Involved in an interior office HQ Project: work on SD, DD, CD; Worked closely with market team and clients. Integrated VR into presentation.

Architectural Intern at WeWork

Feb. 2018 — May 2018 | New York, NY

Worked with professions from tech. Implemented data-driven design approach and research on space & profit efficiency.

Research & Volunteer

Moon Village Jan. — Jul. 2019 | New York, NY

SOM research project (collaborating with Europe Space Agency and MIT) Lumina Pavilion (UVa Bicentennial Celebration) Sep. 2017 — Oct. 2017

Skills

Programming languages

JavaScript (ES6), HTML, CSS

Tools & Platforms

Git, MongoDB, Firebase, Vercel, Netlify, Heroku, Wordpress

Frameworks & Libraries

React, Next.js, Node.js, Express

Design

Figma, Adobe XD, Adobe Creative Suite (Photoshop, InDesign, Illustrator)